A Guide to the House of Delegates Records related to the 375th Anniversary of the First Legislative Assembly in America, 1992-1999
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the House of Delegates Records related to the 375th Anniversary of the First Legislative Assembly in America, 1992-1999
The Library of Virginia
51787
1 cubic foot (1 box)
House of Delegates
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the House of Delegates April 28, 2016. Accessioned May 2, 2016.
Biographical Information
From July 30-August 4, 1619, twenty burgesses convened in the church at Jamestown, marking the beginning of representative government, based on English law and political institutions. This meeting of the first representative legislative assembly in the New World, known as the House of Burgesses, was the antecedent of the present General Assembly, the oldest legislative body in the Western Hemisphere.
Scope and Content
These records document the planning for and documentation of the Commemorative Joint Session of the General Assembly on July 30, 1994 in Jamestown for the observance of the 375th Anniversary of the First Legislative Assembly in British America. These records include correspondence, minutes of the First Legislative Assembly Commemorative Committee, speeches and readings from the session, programs, invitations, and a videotape of the session. After the session, a special journal was printed to commemorate the events of the day.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged in alphabetical order.
Contents List
- Series I. House of Delegates Records related to the 375th Anniversary of the First Legislative Assembly in America, 1992-1999.
  - Biography of the Honorable Betty Boothroyd, Speaker of the House of Commons, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First Legislative Assembly Commemorative Committee meeting agendas and notes, 1993-1994. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guest list, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Information related to previous commemorative events (1919 (300th), 1963 (344th) and 1969 (350th)), 1919-1969. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Informational references, undated. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Press kit, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Printer's mock up of published journal, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Printer's plates for published journal cover (obsverse and reverse of seals of Virginia 1619 and 1776), 1999. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program and schedule of activities, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Receipts and invoices, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Roll calls, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Speeches and readings, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Videotape: 375th Anniversary Commemoration of the Virginia House of Burgesses at Jamestown Settlement, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Published Journal: The 375th Anniversary Jamestown Journal, 1994 July 30. (Box 1, Folder 18)